RISM Collections at New York University Conferences Guide to the Records of New Perspectives on Caribbean Studies: Toward the 21st Century and Prospects for Caribbean Basin Integration (Conference held at Hunter College, CUNY, August 28-September 1, 1984) RISM RG 16 (j)
New York University Archives
- Series XI. Conference Manuscripts (unpublished) June 1984-January 1985
  - Session IX. Regional and International Migration: Development Issues and Policy Implications
    - "The Changing Demography of the Non-Anglo Caribbean," A.J. Jaffe, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - "The Economic Impact of Caribbean Emigration on Labour Donor Societies: Grenada and St. Vincenet," Winston Wiltshire, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, Mss.: "United States Immigration Law and Policy: An Overview," (rev.) Michael Maggio, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - "The Bifurcated Diaspora: an Overview on West Indian migration to the United States and Britain in the Twentieth Century," (rev.) Alistair Hennessy, Oct 1984 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Discussion Remarks: "The Impact, Implications and Special Significance of Caribbean Migration to New York City," Marco Mason, [Aug - Dec 1984] (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Session X. Political Economy of Caribbean Basin Integration
    - "International Relations Aspects of Caribbean Development," Vaughn Lewis [missing], [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - "Up By the Bootstraps: Ideologies of Social Levitation," Frank Bonilla and Ricardo Campos, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - "The Formal and Informal Processes of Caribbean Regional Integration," Rosina Wiltshire-Brodber, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - "U.S. Foreign Policy and the Central Americanization of the English-Speaking Caribbean," Michael Erisman, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - "Some Aspects of Caribbean/Latin American Relations," Don MIlls, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - "Haiti as the New Taiwan of the Caribbean," Paul R. Latortue [missing], [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - "Nationalism vs. Integration: Psychological Resistance," Ramesh Deosaran [missing], [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Discussion Remarks: "The Political Economy of the Caribbean Basin: The Prospects of Integration," Eddie Grenne, Sept 1984; Jan 1985 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Session XI. Caribbean Basin: Crisis, Reaction and Response
    - "The Role of the Church in regional Social Change," Leslie Lett [missing], [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - "The Future of Self-Determination, Sovereignty and Independence in the Caribbean Region: A Discussion," Dessima Williams [missing], Dec 1986; Apr 1987 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - "Guyana: Crisis, Reaction and response," C.Y. Thomas, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - "The Role of the Church in Regional Social Change," Leslie Lett [3], Sept 1984; undated (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Discussion Remarks: "Comments Prepared Caribbean Basin: Crisis, for Session on Reaction Response at Conference on New Perspectives on Caribbean Studies: Toward the 21st Century," Jay R. Mandle, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Session XII. Closing Session and Awards Ceremony
    - "The Impact of the Grenada Invasion," Archie Singham [missing], undated (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Closing remarks: "Address to the research Institute for the Study of man: The Caribbean Basin and regional Development to the 21st Centry," Michael Manley, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence, lectures for Presidential Awards; article re: honoree Edna Manley [missing], Jul - Aug 1984; undated (Box 19, Folder 28)
- Series XII. Yale University Press Manuscripts (unpublished) June 1984 - May 1987
  1.5 linear feet (3 boxes). Arranged as chapters of the proposed publication (see Box 20, Folder 1). This series consists of a select number of conference manuscripts that were revised and reorganized for a planned submission to Yale University Press. Although the planned publication did not materialize, the papers in this series include chapter title pages, indicated in italics, lists of submissions and revised manuscripts.
  - Chapter I. The Nature of Caribbean Society [h4]
    - Proposed publication outline: "West Indian Society One Hundred and Fifty Years After Abolition: Elements of An Interpretation," Lloyd Best, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Original Mss.: "West Indian Society One Hundred and Fifty years After Abolition: Elements of An Interpretation," Lloyd Best, undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Print version of Mss.: "West Indian Society One Hundred and Fifty Years After Abolition: Elements of An Interpretation," Lloyd Best, undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - "Pluralism in the Non-Hispanic Caribbean," (rev.) M. G. Smith, Sept - Oct 1986 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - "Pluralism in the Non-Hispanic Caribbean," (rev.) M. G. Smith, Dec 1986 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - "Pluralism, Politics and Ideology in the Creole Caribbean," (rev.) M. G. Smith, Jan - Feb 1987 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - "Stratification and Social Class in the Hispanic Caribbean (with Special Emphasis On Puerto Rico)," Angel G. Quintero-Rivera, Jul 1984 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - "Class, Race and Culture in the Caribbean: Some Speculations on Theory," Ken Post, undated (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Chapter II. People and Society
    - "Perception as a Factor in the Configuration of Caribbean Social Space," (original and revised copies) Elizabeth M. Thomas-Hope [4], [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - "Social Class and Religion: The Case of Jamaica," Diane J. Austin, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - "Social Class and Religion: The Case of Jamaica," (rev.) Diane J. Austin, [1985] (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - "Religion, Economy and Class in Jamaica: Reinterpreting a Tradition," (rev.) Diane J. Austin, Dec 1986 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - "Twentieth Century Social Struggles in the Caribbean: Black Power and Rastafarianism In Jamaica," Peter D. Phillips, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - "Voodoo and Politics in Contemporary Haiti," (rev.) Michel S. Laguerre, Dec 1986 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - "Political Theatre: Carinval and Cricket in the West Indies," Frank E. Manning, May 1987 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - "Political Theatre: Carnival and Cricket in the West Indies," (rev.) Frank E. Manning, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - "Calypso and Social Confrontation in Trinidad 1970 to the Present," Gordon Rohlehr, Aug 1984; Jan 1985 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - "Cultural Identity and the Arts," Rex Nettleford, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - "Culture and Sovereignty," George Lamming, [Dec 1984]; undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Chapter III. Human and Natural Resources
    - "Population Perspectives of the Commonwealth Caribbean," Jack Harewood, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - "Population Perspectives of the Commonwealth Caribbean," (rev.) Jack Harewood, Mar - Apr 1987 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - "The Changing Demography of the Non-Anglo Caribbean," A. J. Jaffe, Aug - Oct 1984 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - "The Changing Demography of the Non-Anglo Caribbean," (rev.) A. J. Jaffe, Dec 1986; Feb 1987 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - "Some Theoretical Issues in Family and Household Studies," (rev.) R. T. Smith, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - "Some Theoretical Issues in Family and Household Studies," (rev.) R. T. Smith, Sept - Dec 1986 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - "Some Theoretical Issues in Family and Household Studies," (rev.) R. T. Smith, Jan 1987 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - "Health Systems Development in the English-Speaking Caribbean," Peter Carr, Jul 1984 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - "Towards Removal of Constraints to Agricultural Development: Some Perspectives on the Commonwealth Caribbean," E. B. A. St. Cyr and John A. Spence, Aug - Oct 1984 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - "Fuel for the Economy: Energy Investment to Reduce Oil Dependency," (rev.) Verne W. Loose, Beata C. Lewis, Aug - Sept 1984; Dec 1986 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - "Science, Technology and Development in the Caribbean (Possibilities and Impediments)," Aaron Segal and Wallace C. Koehler [note: permission noted on Mss.], 1987 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Chapter IV. Political Economy
    - "Caribbean Sugar Plantations: Their Past, and Their Probable Future," Manuel Moreno Fraginals, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - "Dependency and Local-Level Conflict: Agrarian Processes in Guyana and Coastal Ecuador," Marilyn Silverman, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - "Presence and Decline of the Counter-Plantation System in Dominica," Jean Casimir, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - "Power and Privilege in a Small Island Economy: The Case of Trinidad and Tobago," Carl D. Parris, Aug 1984 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - "Guyana: Crisis, Reaction and Response," C. Y. Thomas, Apr 1987 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - "Up by the Bootstraps: Ideologies of Social Levitation," Frank Bonilla and Ricardo Campos, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - "The Economic Impact of Caribbean Emigration on Labour Donor Societies: Grenada and St. Vincent," Winston Wiltshire, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - "The Plantation Legacy and the Rise, national Corporations in the Caribbean," (rev.) Maurice A. Odle [p. 40 missing], Aug - Dec 1984 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - "Transnational Banks and Crisis in the Capitalist World Economy: Impacts on the Caribbean," Hilbourne A. Watson, May 1983 (Box 22, Folder 11)
- Series XIII. Published Manuscripts
  .5 linear feet (1 box). Arranged chronologically. This series consists of a select number of manuscripts presented at the conference (see Series XI. Conference Manuscripts). Edited by Frank McGlynn, then Associate Professor of Anthropology at the University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg, the papers were included in a special issue entitled "The Social Anthropology of the Contemporary Caribbean" published by the journal Third World Studies. Additional highlights in this series include a draft tribute and partial list bibliographic publications by Vera D. Rubin, written and compiled by Frank McGlynn for the preface (see Folder 1).
  - Correspondence, Preface [tribute to Vera D. Rubin], partial bibliography, Oct 1986 note, Oct 1986; Sept 1985 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - "Voodoo and Politics in Contemporary Haiti," (rev.) Michel S. Laguerre, Dec 1986 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - "The Anthropology of Caribbean Agrarian Formation," Frank McGlynn, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - "Religion, Economy and Class in Jamaica: Reinterpreting A Tradition," (rev.) Diane J. Austin, Dec 1986 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - "Some Theoretical Issues in Family and Household Studies," (rev.) R. T. Smith, Sep 1986 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - "Dependency and Local-Level Conflict: Agrarian Processes in Guyana and Coastal Ecuador," Marilyn Silverman, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - "Political Theatre: Carnival and Cricket in the West Indies," Frank E. Manning, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - "The Transnationalization of Caribbean Migration: Some Political Dynamics," Linda Basch, [Aug - Sept 1984] (Box 23, Folder 8)
- Series XIV. Miscellaneous Articles and Journals
  .5 linear feet (1 box). Arranged chronologically. This series contains articles, newsletters, and journals on a wide range of social and political issues
  - "Can the Haves Meet the Have-Notes Half-Way?" Penny Lernoux, The Nation, Oct 1981 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - "Clinical Undernutrition in the Kingston/ St. Andrew Metropolitan Area," Wilma Bailey [partial], 1981 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Research Note: "A Prospective St Lucian Folk Medicine Survey," Barbara E. Fredrich, Social Science & Medicine, Vol. 15D, 1981 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - "The Caribbean and West Indies Chronicle", Apr - May 1982 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - "Indians and the Guatemalan Revolution," Robert M. Carmack, Cultural Survival Quarterly, Summer 1983 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - "Paraquat and Marijuana: Epidemiologic Risk Assessment," Philip J. Landrigan, American Journal of Public Health, Jul 1983 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - "The Politics of Health Care in Nicaragua before and after the Revolution of 1979," John M. Donahue, Human Organization, Vol. 42, No. 3, Fall 1983 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - "The Impact of the 'Anglo-Guatemala Dispute' On the Internal Politics of Belize," conference paper by Alma H. Young and Dennis H. Young, Sept - Oct 1983 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - "An Amerindian Derivation for Latin American Creole Illnesses and Their Treatment," Audrey Butt Colson and Cesareo de Armellada, Social Science Medicine, Vol. 17, No. 17, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Research Reports: "Concepts in the Anthropological Study of Irrigation," William W. Kelly, American Anthropologist, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - "Remittances and Rural Underdevelopment of the English-Speaking Caribbean," Hymie Rubenstein, Human Organization, Vol. 42, No. 4, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - "The Social and Economic Impacts of the Panama Canal on Barbados," Bonham C. Richardson, Dec 1983 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Tallawah, Vol. 1, No. 2 [newsletter], Feb - Mar 1984 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - "Brief Report of the Advisory Panel on Guatemala," Chris Krueger and Carol A. Smith, Anthropology Newsletter, Vol. 25, No. 3, Mar 1984 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, "Science and Creationism: A View From the National Academy of Sciences Wash., DC: National Academy Press", Apr 1984 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Fight the Right. The Lawlessness of Reagan, [issue] No. 2, Jun 1984 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - "Tourism and Food Imports: Jamaica," Francois J. Belisle, Economic Development and Cultural Change, University of Chicago, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - "Between Two Worlds," Virginia E. Sanchez Korrol, "Notes on the Reconquest. The Latin Americanization of the United States?" Alejandro Portes, Caribbean Review, undated (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - "How Cricket Is West Indian Cricket, Class, Racial, and Color Conflict," L. O'Brien Thompson, Caribbean Review[partial], undated (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Various book lists and reviews, undated (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous, 1983, 1984, undated (Box 23, Folder 29)
- Series XV. Oversized Materials, July 1983 - September 1984
  Approximately 1.6 linear feet (1 oversize box). Arranged chronologically. This series is mainly comprised of oversized and/or unique conference posters and original newspaper articles.
  - "Wilberforce Anniversary Events in the University of Hull, International Conference, Legacies of West Indian Slavery," conference poster, Jul 1983 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - "U.S. Moves a Carrier into Caribbean," The New York Times, "Tensions Revealed in Roosevelt-Churchill Letters," The New York Times "Democrats Can Seize Central America" July 1984 New York Times, Jul 1984 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - "Maurice Bishop Speaks," Carib News, N.Y., Aug 1984 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - "New Perspectives on The Caribbean," Carib News, N.Y., Sep 1984 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - "Hunter College Honours W. Indians," The Sunday Gleaner, Sep 1984 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - "Sparrow Honoured by U.S. University," The Sunday Gleaner, Sep 1984 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - "For Mexicans, Concern Rises on Civil Rights," The New York Times, Sept 1984 (Box 24, Folder 7)
- Series XVI. Audio and Video Recordings, August 1984 - March 1985
  Approximately 2 linear feet (2 Paige boxes). This series contains 26 videotapes, 26 digibeta copies of the videotapes as well as 26 DVD copies of videotapes, 60 original audiotapes and 60 CD copies of original audiotapes. All tapes are arranged in numerical sequence. The videotapes are labeled with the prefix "68768" followed by the tape number (i.e.68768/1). The inventory treats the second number as the tape number. Series XVII. Digitized Audio and Video Recordings and Transcripts contains digitized copies of these audio and video recordings, transcripts, and indices to the audio and video transcripts.
  - Audio Tapes
    - "8/29, Tape 1 Playhouse. 9:30-12:30," Side A: Joseph Murphy, Vera D. Rubin, Lloyd Best; Side B: Manuel Moreno Fraginals, Maurice A. Odle. [tape is missing], undated (Box 25, Cassette 1)
    - "8/29, Tape 2 Playhouse. 9:30-12:30," Side A: Jay R. Mandle, Patrick I. Gomes, Jean Casimir, George L. Beckford, Norman P. Girvan, C. Y. Thomas; Side B: no listing [tape is missing], undated (Box 25, Cassette 2)
    - "Theoretical and Applied Issues in Social Organization," Aug 29, Afternoon session, Tape 1," Side A: no listing; Side B: no listing, undated (Box 25, Cassette 3)
    - "Theoretical and Applied Issues in Social Organization," Aug 29, Afternoon session, Tape 2," Side A: no listing; Side B: no listing, undated (Box 25, Cassette 4)
    - "On Stratification, Pluralism and Sociopolitical Dynamics," Aug 29, Afternoon session, Tape 1," Side A: M. G. Smith, Ken Post; Side B: Demetrio Boersner, Angel G.Quintero-Rivera, Suzy Castor., undated (Box 25, Cassette 5)
    - "On Stratification, Pluralism and Sociopolitical Dynamics," (cont.) Aug 29, Afternoon session, Tape 2, undated (Box 25, Cassette 6)
    - "On Stratification, Pluralism and Sociopolitical Dynamics," (cont.) Aug 29, Afternoon session, Tape 3, Side A: Suzy Castor, Michel S. Laguerre, Andres Serbin, Lloyd Braithwaite, Eric R. Wolf; Side B: no listing, undated (Box 25, Cassette 7)
    - "Theoretical & Applied Issues in Social Organization," Side A: Elizabeth M. Thomas-Hope Holt [sic] [Elizabeth M. Thomas-Hope] (0 - 400), Merle Hodge (418 - end of side and first part of side B); Side B: [Merle Hodge (000-62)], "'Nationalism, Independence & Creative Florescence,' Tape 3," Wilfred Cartey (63 - 403), George Lamming (730 - end, continues on Tape 9), undated (Box 25, Cassette 8)
    - "Nationalism, Independence and Creative Florescence," Tape 2, Side A: George Lamming (cont.) (000 - 154), Rex Nettleford (166- end); Side B: Frank E. Manning (500 - 715), Gordon Rohlehr (723 - end), undated (Box 25, Cassette 9)
    - "'Nationalism, Independence and Creative Florescence,' Tape 3," Side A: Gordon Rohlehr (000 - 230), Errol Hill (245 - ), undated (Box 25, Cassette 10)
    - "'Process of Ethnicity,' Aug 30, Tape 1," Aug 30, Tape 1," Side A: no listing; Side B: no listing, undated (Box 25, Cassette 11)
    - "'Process of Ethnicity,' Aug 30, Tape 2," Aug 30, Tape 1," Side A: no listing; Side B: no listing, undated (Box 25, Cassette 12)
    - "'Process of Ethnicity,' Aug 30, Tape 1," Aug 30, Tape 1," Side A: no listing; Side B: no listing, undated (Box 25, Cassette 13)
    - "'Health in the Caribbean and Central America,'" Aug 31, Tape 1," Side A: no listing; Side B: no listing, undated (Box 25, Cassette 14)
    - "'Health in the Caribbean and Central America,' Aug 31, Tape 2," Side A: Peter Carr; Side B: no listing, undated (Box 25, Cassette 15)
    - "'Health in the Caribbean and Central America," Aug 31, Tape 3, first part of Side A: no listing (000 - 204) "Regional and International Migration" (205 - end), Saskia Sassen-Koob, Linda Basch; Side B: Linda Basch (cont.), Michel S. Laguerre, Jack Harewood, undated (Box 25, Cassette 16)
    - "'Public Health Indices of Development,' Tape 1, Side A: no listing; Side B: "Regional and International Migration," Michel S. Laguerre "(intra-Haitian migration)", undated (Box 25, Cassette 17)
    - "Regional and International Migration," Aug 31, Tape 2," Side A: no listing; Side B: no listing, undated (Box 25, Cassette 18)
    - "'Regional and International Migration,' Aug 31, Tape 3," Sides A: no listing; Side B: no listing, undated (Box 25, Cassette 19)
    - "Political Economy and Sociocultural Change," Aug 31, Tape 1, Side A: Roy Brice-Laporte, Peter D. Phillips (427 - ); Side B: Peter D. Phillips (cont.) (000 - 274), Jose Moreno (274 - end), undated (Box 25, Cassette 20)
    - "Political Economy and Sociocultural Change," Aug 31, Tape 2, Side A: Jose Moreno (000 - 032), Hilbourne A. Watson (032 - 443), Gérard Pierre-Charles (473 - end); Side B: Gérard Pierre-Charles (cont.) (000 - end), undated (Box 25, Cassette 21)
    - "Political Economy and Sociocultural Change," Aug 31, Tape 3, Side A: Locksley Edmondson (000 - 290), Kenneth Erickson (292 - 401), Eddie Greene (410 - 516), Open discussion; Side B: Open Discussion (cont.), 1992 (Box 25, Cassette 22)
    - "Agriculture and New Technologies: Dependency and Self- Reliance," Tape 1, Side A: Aaron Segal, Trevor M. A. Farrell; Side B: Trevor M. A. Farrell (cont.), Verne W. Loose, Lawrence A. Wilson, undated (Box 25, Cassette 23)
    - "Agriculture and New Technologies: Dependency and Self-Reliance," Tape 2, Side A: Gerald F. Murray, undated (Box 25, Cassette 24)
    - "'Political Economy of the Caribbean Basin Integration,' Sept 1, Tape 1," Side A: no listing; Side B: no listing, undated (Box 25, Cassette 25)
    - "Political Economy of the Caribbean Basin Integration," Sept 1, Tape 2," Side A: no listing; Side B: no listing, undated (Box 25, Cassette 26)
    - "'Caribbean Basin: Crisis, Reaction and Response,' Sept 1, Tape 1," Side A: "A.M. sesson"; Side B: C. Y. Thomas, Leslie Lett, undated (Box 25, Cassette 27)
    - "'Caribbean Basin: Crisis, Reaction and Response,' Sept 1, Tape 2," Side A: Archie Singham, Dessima Williams; Side B: Dessima Williams (cont.), Lucille Mair, Jay R. Mandle, Rickey Singh, undated (Box 25, Cassette 28)
    - "'Caribbean Basin: Crisis, Reaction and Response,' Sept 1, Tape 3," Side A: Jorge Sol, Michael Manley; Side B: Michael Manley (cont.), Award Ceremony, undated (Box 25, Cassette 29)
    - "'Caribbean Basin: Crisis, Reaction and Response," Sept 1, Tape 4," Side A: "Award Ceremony"; Side B: no listing, undated (Box 25, Cassette 30)
    - "Caribbean Tapes Sample Rough" (audio) sample transfer, undated (Box 25, Cassette 31)
  - Video Tape Shelf List
    - "Caribbean Tapes Selects I" [missing], undated (Box 26, Reel 68768/1)
    - "Caribbean Basin: Crisis Reaction and Response, Playhouse (live) Session, Clive Thomas [C. Y. Thomas], Roy Neehall, Archie Singham, Roll 1 (complete)", undated (Box 26, Reel 68768/2)
    - "Caribbean Tapes Selects II", undated (Box 26, Reel 68768/3)
    - "Session I. (25 min.) Symbolic Expressions in Politics (cont.) Original, Tape 2, Camera 1" [Haitian Interview], undated (Box 26, Reel 68768/4)
    - "Caribbean Conflict and Response, Original, Tape 6A, Camera 2", undated (Box 26, Reel 68768/5)
    - "Caribbean Conflict and Response (cont.), Original, Tape 6, Camera 1", undated (Box 26, Reel 68768/6)
    - "Session I. Symbolic Expressions in Politics, Original, Tape 1A, Camera 2", undated (Box 26, Reel 68768/7)
    - "Session I. Symbolic Expressions in Politics, (cont.) Original, Tape 2A, Camera 2" [Haitian Interview], undated (Box 26, Reel 68768/8)
    - "Caribbean Oil, Original, Tape 7, Single Camera", undated (Box 26, Reel 68768/9)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 26, Reel 68768/10)
    - "The Caribbean Today: Obstacles to Change, Camera 1", undated (Box 26, Reel 68768/11)
    - "The Caribbean Today: Obstacles to Change, Camera 2", undated (Box 26, Reel 68768/12)
    - "Caribbean Conference, Caribbean Crisis, Saturday afternoon, Live Session, Roll One: Clive Thomas [C. Y. Thomas], Roy Neehall, Archie Singham, undated (Box 26, Reel 68768/13)
    - "Caribbean Conference, Caribbean Crisis, Saturday afternoon, Live Session, Roll One, Clive Thomas [C. Y. Thomas], Roy Neehall, Archie Singham; Playhouse Session, Roll 2, Camera 1", undated (Box 27, Reel 68768/14)
    - "Caribbean Conference, 'Caribbean Crisis,' Saturday afternoon, Live Session, Camera 1, Tape 3", undated (Box 27, Reel 68768/15)
    - "End of Manley's [Micheael Manley] Speech, Awards and speech by George Lamming," Tape 4 (end of playhouse [session])", undated (Box 27, Reel 68768/16)
    - "Caribbean Conference, Saturday, Live Session, panelists, audience, Dessima Williams, undated (Box 27, Reel 68768/17)
    - "Caribbean Conference, Saturday, Live Session, Manley [Michael Manley], Camera 2, Roll 3, (000-782)", undated (Box 27, Reel 68768/18)